<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A programmer&#39;s viewpoint</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A programmer&#39;s viewpoint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NPS - Exploratory analysis in R</title>
      <link>/2017/nps-exploratory-analysis-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/nps-exploratory-analysis-in-r/</guid>
      <description>NPS analysis What is NPS Net Promoter Score or NPS is a customer loyalty metric and was developed by Fred Reichheld and it asks respondents to answer a single question. “How likely are you to recommend this product?” The respondents are asked to score between 0 and 10. 10 being “most likely” to recommend and 0 being “least likely”.
An additional optional question is asked about why they picked this score and the response to that is usually a text comment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access log parsing with Spark and schema extraction from query string</title>
      <link>/2016/access-log-parsing-with-spark-and-schema-extraction-from-query-string/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/access-log-parsing-with-spark-and-schema-extraction-from-query-string/</guid>
      <description>I needed to parse server logs and create Spark DataFrames to query information from the query string parameters. My naive version kept throwing errors about mismatched number of fields in schema and those in the row being queried.
It turns out I was dealing with over 350 different query string params across the logs. This could change over time and there was no way I was going to add these programmatically by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Marketplaces and platforms</title>
      <link>/2014/on-marketplaces-and-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/on-marketplaces-and-platforms/</guid>
      <description>Marketplaces are all the rage these days, in truth, marketplaces have been around since ancient times. A marketplace usually exists to connect sellers of goods or services with buyers. The marketplace itself usually benefits by selling space to sellers or by taking a cut of the transaction.
This post is focused on service marketplaces that are connecting and democratizing human capital in a way that has never been possible. Things like vetting, payments, reviews and support have been researched and A/B tested to an art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding with find</title>
      <link>/2013/finding-with-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/finding-with-find/</guid>
      <description>Find is a really versatile utility that can be used to enumerate files of different types, narrow the list by file types, dates, sizes, access times and a whole list of expressions. The output can be formatted with various switches to be csv.
My goal was to list the sizes and access times for all video files in the system. I knew that there was over 3 TB of files but not how recently these were accessed/played.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>